registerednursern.com 2019-12-09

# RegisteredNurseRN.com Privacy Policy

We care about your privacy and want to provide transparency to our visitors. This page will outline the privacy policy for RegisteredNurseRN.com, and by using or accessing this website and its related products and services, you agree to our privacy policy below, as well as our [terms of service](https://www.registerednursern.com/legal-disclosure/).

  * **We do NOT sell or rent your personal information to third parties**. However, in the event of a sale or transfer of this website, any information you have provided to us will be transferred to the new owner so that they can continue to provide you with access to this site and its related resources.
  * **We use third party website scripts** , plugins, ad programs, and analytics data to add functionality to this site such as quizzes, contact forms, and so forth, which may collect some basic information from you each time you visit our site, as described on this page.
  * **Please do not submit, post, or store** sensitive personal information on or through our website that could be potentially compromised. Although we use a hosting company with strong security protocols in place, even the most secure website could become compromised. It is your responsibility to use “best practices” to keep your sensitive information safe and private. For example, for online use, create throwaway email accounts and have them forward emails to your main account. Refrain from using your full name, address, and other personal information unless absolutely necessary. Use pseudonyms or nicknames when posting online. Run a good antivirus program on your computer regularly, and use secure connections when accessing the internet.

## Personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address, and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Cookies are also used by advertising programs, affiliate programs, as well as the other tools or plugins described on this page below.

### Google advertising cookies

We deliver advertisements on our website via Google’s Adsense program, which may use cookies to serve the best ads related to your interest. Here is [Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/), as well as information from Google:

Google uses cookies to help serve the ads it displays on the websites of its partners, such as websites displaying Google ads or participating in Google certified ad networks. When users visit a Google partner’s website, a cookie may be dropped on that end user’s browser.

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website or other websites.
  * Google’s use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). (Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).)

The Google ad program allows [third-party vendors or ad networks](https://support.google.com/dfp_premium/answer/94149) to serve ads on our site, and we have opted into all of the [Certified Google Ad Networks](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/9012903) through our Adsense dashboard. Please visit those links to learn more about Google’s advertising partners, their respective privacy policies, and how to opt out. Again, you can opt out of some third-party vendors’ uses of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

### Amazon Affiliate Program

RegisteredNurseRN.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to products on amazon.com. These links contain a special code that may be stored in the user’s browser, which notifies Amazon that the referral came from our website.

Any time you click an affiliate link on our site and make a purchase, you could potentially earn us an affiliate commission (at no extra cost to you), which helps support our site. Amazon.com does not disclose any personal information to us after this event (such as names or addresses of buyers), other than aggregated sales data such as daily sales and referral commissions we might have earned.

For more information about the information Amazon collects, please visit [Amazon’s privacy policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496).

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to track data such as keywords used to find our website, pages visited, demographics of visitors such as country of origin, date of access, IP address, browser, device used, page views, and other basic information that can help us improve or analyze our website. Google Analytics uses cookies to determine or record this information. To learn the exact data collected, means of storage, and so forth, you may read [Google Analytics’ privacy policy.](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)

We do not rent, sell, lease, or share our Google Analytics data with third parties, and it would only be transferred in the event of a business/website sale or transfer.

### Jetpack Plugin

We use the Jetpack WordPress plugin by Automattic to add functionality to our website, including the following:

  * **Social sharing buttons** , which allow visitors to share content on their social media profiles.
  * **Basic analytics data** , which reveal to us limited information such as visitors per day, keywords used, pages visited, links clicked, and more.
  * **Because of this** , Jetpack may use cookies, IP addresses, or other methods to detect and record such information.

Please see [Jetpack’s privacy policy](https://jetpack.com/support/privacy/) for specific information about how they collect and handle your information.

### Email Post Notifications

We use Google Feedburner’s email notification service to send “new article” alerts to users who have opted into the free service. When you sign up for free email notifications, your email address is sent to (and stored) on Google’s Feedburner website. You can opt out of email notifications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email. We do not share your email address with others. For more information, please see [Google Feedburner’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

### Log Files / Hosting Services

In addition to our Jetpack plugin and Google Analytics, our hosting company may collect log file information as a security precaution.  The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site. We currently use [Websynthesis by Studiopress](https://www.studiopress.com/privacy-policy/), and you can view their privacy policy by clicking the link.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

In addition, by submitting a comment, you agree that we may use comments or messages in marketing promotions or to answer questions in videos or in articles.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact Forms and Quizzes

Our website utilizes a WordPress plugin that provides contact form and quiz functionality. The contact form will collect whatever information you provide when trying to contact us, such as your name, email address, message, etc. This information will be sent to our personal email address and stored in our database on our server, which is emptied regularly. Please do not enter sensitive information into our website, such as credit cards, social security number, personal address, or any other information that you would not want to be potentially compromised.

In addition, the contact form and quizzes automatically record information when viewed on a page (or submitted), such as IP address, date of submission, quiz scores, form views, form ID, data you selected or entered into the form or quiz, and time of submission (or form view). This information is stored in our server’s database only, and it is deleted at routine intervals (no longer than 6 months, often much sooner).

We do not sell or rent this data, and the only time we look at form meta data is when someone alerts us to a potential quiz error or other technical problem.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. YouTube videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. YouTube videos are regularly embedded on our site, and you can read [YouTube’s privacy policy](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy_guidelines&hl=en&visit_id=1-636627087352862807-67309279&rd=1) for more information. We may also embed tweets, Instagram pictures, and other similar social information.

Please refer to the privacy policy of websites or organizations we may reference, quote, or embed onto our website for more information.

## Who we share your data with

We do not sell or rent your data to third parties. Our sharing is only to provide content for free, record basic analytics data, or to show advertisements, and is limited to the following:

  * Google’s ad program uses the cookies to display ads, as described above. Because we post their ad code into our website, they will access some of your information via cookies. The third party Google certified ad networks will also have access to this information.
  * Information is sent to Google Analytics software, as described above.
  * Information is used by our plugins that stay stored on our server, such as Jetpack, contact forms, quizzes, and so forth.
  * We pay for hosting services, and we have no control over software or information gathering that our hosting company may use.
  * Feedburner’s service stores your email when you opt in, but you may unsubscribe at any time by following their instructions in the email itself.
  * Amazon’s affiliate program reads cookies or special link URLs to track affiliate referrals.
  * Sharing plugins through Jetpack allow you to share our content on our social media.
  * In the event of legal issues, audits, or law enforcement requests, we may be forced to share data.
  * In the event of nefarious activity, such as hacking or trying to harm our website or website visitors in any way, we may turn over information we have to the appropriate authorities.
  * In the event of a technical problem, we may have to hire or consult technicians or web hosting support staff and provide them with temporary access to our databases and websites for the purposes of troubleshooting and repair.

## How long we retain your data

  * Data gathered and stored in our database through contact form submissions or quiz software are automatically deleted from our database no later than every 6 months, often much sooner as a part of routine maintenance (weekly or monthly).
  * Emails sent to our email address from contact forms or direct messages are retained indefinitely if there is a need for future correspondence, though we might delete some irrelevant emails sooner or if the user requests deletion.
  * Google Feedburner will store your email address indefinitely, unless you opt out of the free email notification service.
  * Information gathered by Google Analytics is set to be purged every 26 months.
  * If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely on pages on our website and/or database. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
  * For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
  * For information about third party data retention from our partners and tools listed above (Google Adsense, Analytics, Jetpack plugin, website hosting, Amazon affiliate, or embedded content providers), please visit their respective privacy policy for their data retention policy.

## What rights you have over your data, opting out, and data deletion requests

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

**Data Requests:**

  * To request data used from any of the third parties we use on our website (Google Adsense, Amazon.com, Jetpack Plugin, Google Analytics, etc) you’ll need to contact them directly.

**Opting Out:**

  * You can stop receiving free email notifications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in the emails.
  * You may opt out of cookies by adjusting browser settings, visiting appropriate ad pages linked above, and other methods. However, because our site uses Javascript, cookies, and other means to provide core site functionality, a total rejection of cookies, scripts, and analytics tracking records means that our website would become unusable.

**Data Deletion Requests:**

  * To delete your email address from the opt-in email notification, click “unsubscribe” from within the email.
  * To delete your form submissions or quiz submissions, you can request that we purge our database sooner. However, we routinely purge all form and quiz submissions from the database and do not sell or share such information.
  * To delete cookies, you can adjust or delete them in your browser, and then cease to use this website.
  * To delete comments or other information you might have submitted to us, you can use the contact form to submit your request.
  * To delete messages or comments left on social media sites, please log into your social media accounts and delete the information.

## Where we send your data

  * Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
  * Email notification sign-ups are routed to Google’s Feedburner email notification service.
  * Contact form submissions are routed to our email address and also stored on our database, along with quiz metadata.
  * Sharing tools send information to your social media accounts.
  * Using the “search our videos” search box will sent queries to YouTube’s search.
  * Again, information is sent to the following: Google Analytics, Jetpack by Automattic, Google Adsense and their partners, Amazon Affiliate program, and the other services mentioned on this page.

Because we do not charge for access to our videos, quizzes, and notes, we ask that you do not use ad block technology or disable cookie access for ad programs. If you do not agree to this privacy policy, please cease from using our website.
